

Eduard Kvak

Senior Product Designer

With 7+ years of experience, I focus on creating thoughtful, user-centered solutions. I enjoy working closely with teams to build intuitive products that meet both user needs and business goals. I'm excited to bring my skills to a new challenge where design directly impacts outcomes.

O Cologne, Germany

49 157 33698452

in Linkedin

☑ Portfolio

Work Experience

Car IQ Inc. / Lead Senior Product Designer

Oct 2022 - Aug 2024 (San Francisco, Remote)

- Led the design team of 3 designers, created and distributed tasks, approved design solutions, doubling team output.
- Created design systems, documentation, guidelines, and set up design principles that decreased the design process time by ~40%.
- Conducted data analysis, user testing and interviews, A/B testing, created and tested hypotheses, etc. resulting in a ~60% improvement in usability and user engagement.
- Collaborated with developers, conducted design QA, set up bug tracker system, reducing the sprint release issues by ~35%.
- Created mobile/web applications, integrations, white-labels, increasing SUS score to 82,8% and task completion rate to 93.6%.
- Collaborated with other departments, participated in product growth/monetisation and brought the product to the market leaders.

Cieden / Lead Senior Product Designer

Jun 2021 - Oct 2022 (Lviv, Ukraine / Toronto, Canada)

- Led the design team of 4 designers, hiring new designers, and assisting with managing internal company structure.
- · Led the calls with clients and stakeholders.
- Conducted data analysis, competitor/user researches, audits, user testing/interviews, created and tested hypotheses.
- · Created mobile/web applications, prototypes, design systems, documentation, and guidelines.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Conducted knowledge sharings and lectures for team members.
- Participated in the pre-sales stage.

Excited / Product Designer

May 2020 - Mar 2021 (Lviv, Ukraine)

- Led the calls with clients and stakeholders.
- · Conducted data analysis, competitor/user researches, audits, created and tested hypotheses.
- · Created mobile/web applications, prototypes, design systems.
- Conducted knowledge sharings for team members.

Sigma Software Group / UX/UI Designer

Sep 2019 - May 2020 (Lviv, Ukraine)

- · Participated in the calls with clients and stakeholders.
- Conducted data analysis, competitor/user researches, audits.
- Created mobile/web applications, prototypes, design systems.
- · Created printing materials, branding, logos, presentation templates.
- · Created video materials and animations.

FocusWeb Studio / UX/UI Designer

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019 (Lviv, Ukraine)

- Participated in the calls with clients and stakeholders.
- · Conducted competitor/user researches, audits.
- · Created mobile/web applications, landing/corporate websites.

Education

Lviv Polytechnic National University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering

Smart Interface Patterns

Deep examination of common components and design patterns in modern interfaces — desktop and mobile. Advanced configurators, Complex tables, Maps, Data Visualization, and more.

Inclusive Web Design

Study of WCAG guidelines. Practicing in creating the user-friendly interface for inclusive users.

Skills & Toolset

UX/UI & Graphic tools:

Figma, Sketch, Adobe Creative Suite, Miro, Whimsical, Zeroheight.

Analytics:

Google analytics, Pendo, Hotjar, Qualitative methods, Quantitative methods, Researches.

UX frameworks:

Problem definition, Strategic thinking, Product growth, Design thinking approach, Heuristic evaluation, UX strategy, Data-driven management, Customer journey map, User flow, A/B testing, Usability testing.

UI & Interaction design:

Web app design, Responsive/Adaptive design, Mobile app design (iOS & Android), White label, Apple CarPlay/Android Auto/AAOS, Integrations, Embedded systems, Design system/Design documentation, Guidelines, Prototyping, Accessibility.

Additional skills:

Team management, Mentoring, HTML/CSS basics, JavaScript basics.

Languages

English	Proficient
German	Beginner
Ukrainian	Native